Ron Wynn

216-235-5874 <u>rcwynn@gmail.com</u> Cleveland, Ohio <u>www.linkedin.com/in/roncwynn</u>

IT Architect/Software Developer/Team Leader

Experienced IT Architect with over 25 years of experience ranging from senior developer to SharePoint Architect and Practice Director. After years of involvement with SharePoint I am looking to shift gears and use my skills and experience in the software development arena.

Leadership Skills

- Team Leader
- Project Management
- Performance Reviews
- Requirements Gathering
- Effort Estimation
- Problem Solving

- Strategic Planning
- Risk Management
- Quality Assurance
- Large Group Presentations
- Whiteboarding
- User Training

Technical Skills

- C#.NET
- .NET CORE
- ASP.NET
- OOP
- MVC
- Git/GitHub
- Agile & SCRUM
- TDD

- HTML
- CSS
- XML
- JavaScript
- JSON
- Web API
- REST/RESTful
- Node.JS

- Visual Studio
- SQL Server
- SharePoint
 - Architecture
 - Development
- VMware
- Nintex
- PowerShell

Industry Experience

WeCan{Code}IT, Cleveland, OH

Software Developer – May 2020 to Present

Currently engaged in a 5-star-rated coding boot camp, learning full-stack development from expert instructors and intensive hands-on projects. This camp is allowing me to brush up on the programming and development skills I used early on in my career as well as learn some new skills in a collaborative team-based as well as independent setting.

Wynning Edge Woodcraft

Owner – October 2017 to Present

- Developed and executed large scale home renovations for over 25 clients
- Invested in and completed short-term home investments/remodels with partner investors
- Built custom furniture and woodcraft projects to meet client specifications and expectations

Ron Wynn - IT Architect/Software Developer/Team Leader

Vertex Computer Systems

Director of SharePoint Services - November 2014 to October 2017

- · Lead a team of SharePoint professionals during the entire lifecycle of client engagements
- · Reviewed team assignments, lead internal and external meetings, and worked directly with clients
- Designed and Implemented a 20,000 user SharePoint 2013 Enterprise System

Parker Hannifin

SharePoint Architect & Project Manager - May 2013 to November 2014

- Designed, built and lead development team for a 50,000 user SharePoint 2010 Enterprise System
- Analyzed and re-built existing SharePoint system to enhance performance and reliability
- Designed and configured environment to support Third party add-on solutions

HMB, Inc.

SharePoint Architect & Practice Lead - Feb 2012 to May 2013

- Lead the SharePoint Consulting Practice
- Architected dozens of complex client engagements
- Mentored junior consultants

Hyland Software, Inc.

SharePoint Architect/Developer - Apr 2007 to Feb 2012

- Lead all planning, development, and implementation of internal SharePoint projects
- Consulted with OnBase developers on SharePoint development integrations
- Designed and developed organization-wide .NET/C# internal SharePoint solutions

Other Positions

- Progressive Insurance 2004 to 2006
 - o Project Manager/SharePoint Analyst
- Pioneer-Standard Electronics 1999 to 2003
 - o Department Manager/Senior Developer
- CIBER Systems 1998 to 1999
 - o Senior Visual Basic Developer/Consultant
- National City Corporation 1997 to 1998
 - Senior Visual Basic Developer
- KeyBank 1992 to 1997
 - Senior Visual Basic Developer
- Real Estate Agent 2003 to 2004; 2006 to 2007

Education & Training

- We Can Code IT Certificate of Software Development, 2020
- SharePoint 2010 Configuration MCTS(Exam 70-667), 2011
- SharePoint 2010 Administration MCIPT(Exam 70-668), 2011
- Bowling Green State University BS, Computer Science, 1992